











BHARATHKUMARRAJU DASARAJU

SENIOR SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER - ADVANCE.AI. SINGAPORE

ONLINE CONTACT

Singapore https://bharathkumaraju.com t: +65 90829964 in in.linkedin.com/in/dasararaju

github.com/bharathkumarraju/, cka.devops4itengineers.com email: bhrth.dsra1@gmail.com

SUMMARY:

Over 11 years IT experience in **DevOps** and **CLOUD** in mission critical environments across the Streaming ,Aviation, Financial, Telecommunications, Financial and GPS industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem-solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, automation, continuous deployment(CICD) pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

TECHNICAL PROFILE:

DevOps Google cloud, AWS Cloud, Azure, Ansible, Terraform, Git, ArgoCD, Hashicorp vault, github actions, Kubernetes, Docker

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Functionbeat, Logstash, Filebeat, metricbeat

Python, Shell Scripting. **Programming RDBMS** Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu, Coreos, Redhat Atomic

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform. Certifications AWS Solution Architect, Google cloud professional architect, Terraform certified professional,

Certified kubernetes administrator .

EXPERIENCE:

Singapore(2021)

(2020)

Advance.ai Working on ArgoCD gitops approach to deploy containerized apps to GKE clusters.

Singapore(2022) Deployed Microservices Using Helm charts in the GKE cluster &managed secrets in HCV

Designed entire Infrastructure/networking for Safi Bank in GCP using terraform.

Developed CICD through GitHub Actions. Used ARGOCD as a CD tool with ISTIO-mesh

Automated the AWS account creation using AWS lambda, SNS and SES under AWS Organizations. Singtel Automate the infrastructure using pulumi in google cloud using python programming with TDD.

Deploying the containerized apps in both AWS and GoogleCloud using CICD with GHA.

Dockerized the applications and moved them from GCE VMs to cloud run serverless in Google cloud. NTUC

CICD Pipeline using Bitbucket pipelines to promote deployments seamlessly.

Singapore Implemented IAC(Infrastructure As a Code) using terraform for google cloud. Implemented

Automated AWS Cloud deployments and builds using the github actions. **HOOQ TV**

Implemented IAC(Infrastructure As a Code) using terraform for AWS cloud were dockerized apps are running. Singapore

(2019-2020) Working on openshift container platform to move legacy apps to k8s.

Implemented CICD pipeline using AWS codecommit, codebuild and codedeploy. SingaporeAirlines. Singapore(2019) Worked in sourced consumables and implemented custom resources in AWS CFT.

Automated Bamboo deployments and builds using the Bamboo specs.

Delivion GmBH, Implemented automated backup solution for complex applications. Essen, Germany

Worked in k8s setup using kubespray and federated Prometheus monitoring for the k8s cluster and apps. (2018-2019)

Automated complex webmethods provisioning using ansible with Jenkins CICD. Standard Chartered,

Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic Stack. Chennai, India Worked in Openshift container platform. (2016-2018)

Worked on Immutable automated deployments using Cliqr. Created Development, QA, Stage, Production stacks & Trimble, Chennai, maintained them securely using robust VPC design. Automated resource cleanup using AWS Lambda as part of cost saving India (2014-2016)

effort. Implemented infra, application monitoring using datadog and logging using sumologic.

Hewlett-Packard Chennai, India(2011-2014) Administered DHCP,DNS, LDAP, AD and NFS services on RHEL in Development/Production environments. Automated the apache/tomcat web/app applications installation and configuration using shell scripts. Supported the tomcat/jboss applications running on unix/linux servers.

EDUCATION:

MCA-Post Graduation Information System and Computer Science.

(Jun2007-Jun2010) UNIX Networking, Java, Information Systems, information security, e-business

BSC- Graduation Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

(Jul2004-May2007) Courses: Applied Mathematics, Organic Chemistry, Atomic Physics

LANGUAGES: Fluent in English, Telugu, Tamil, Hindi, German.

INTERESTS: Technology trends and news, travelling, football, movies.